<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-new-century-celebrations</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83040340/1899-12-29/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
  <text>THE GLAD NEW YEAR.
Its Advent Is Marked by Various
Customs In Many Lands.
MOHICattenl
in our nu
ton, than
ent ion is paid to New Year's
utional capital. Washing-
in any olhet city in the
L mted states. lhc state levee at the
white house is but the beginning of thu
calling that continues throughout the aft
ernoon and well into the night in ollicial
and private homes. In fact, the social
season is formally inaugurated on New
Year's day It is grand rail) ing day, and
men call then who never eincige Iroiii their
shell again during the jear. Lists uie
published .n the newspapers of the houses
where iettkt.ioiis will be held, with the
names of the assisting women. The latter
often attract more cal.crs than the hostess,
and newly arrived families aieon the look,
out for popular women for their receptions.
The allairs are conducted with lavish south
ern hospitality Tables are loaded with
viands real southern egg-nog or bowls of
Fish House punch mixed by a well-guarded
formula, an heirloom in the family , is
served. It is a gala day for Washington, and
It it well it comes but once a year.
New Year's day it made much of in
Europe, and in some countries its celebra
tion is on a more elaborate scale than
Christmas, Gifts are exchanged with reck
less abandon, recalling the days of feudal
ism, when every landlord presented his ten
ant with a fat capon An orange stuck with
cloves was the common gift of poor people.
Among the rich, gloves were a popular pres
ent, and often a sum of money, called glove
money, served as a substitute. When pins
were invented they took the place of gloves,
and every woman was protitl of her collec
tion of pins made from thorns, bone, silver,
gold or steel. The expression, pin money,
was originally used to designate the money
often presented in lieu of the pins for their
purchase. ITnder good Queen Hess the
custom of giving presents on New Vear's
was at its high water matk, and the most
extravagant packages were distributed an
onymously with no inscription but a verse
expressing gieetings,
According to an old itiperstilion, one't
luck for the year Is dependent on the com
plexion of the first man who enlls. If ho
is a blonde, fate will be kind, bm if a
dark-complexioned man steps over the
threshold lirst, sickness, trouble mid finan
cial disaster are apt to step with liiiu. So
firmly was this superstition implanted in
the mind of an elderly woman that she
made arrangement! every year by which
ber first caller was sure to be of a light
coraulcxlnu.
Thr ho' ,(,n revels in L'ngland end w t!i
T'ci'-tl, ight J,, America thev me
drawn H ,,, ,,-itli the N- year
celebration. The snipping of tin Christ
mas tree; which properly takes place ,W
dear's Kve, is fteqtiently made the ex
cuse for a jollv party. Theic is very
likely to be a package nn the tree for
each one present, "nntuiinng a joke that will
be as good-natured is it is amusing.
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045555/1899-12-30/ed-1/seq-18/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
  <text>THE FIRST HAPPY NEW YEAR GREETING GREETINGFrom
I
11
From the Earliest Ages Men Have Gelebrated the Day as an anOccasion anOccasion anOccasion
Occasion for Congratulations and Good Wishes
All notions twin to have agreed agreedTil
11 Til i ilnee the memory of man runneth not notto notIb nottu
to the contrary to observe the lint day dayof dayot dayof
of the year as nn occasion occa lon of festivity festivityand
and mutual good wishes When hen or how howthis howthis howibis
this oustom originated history does not nottell notloll nottell
tell It antedates history and extends extendsI
I I far back Into the age of fable Hun Hunreds IIundreds
1 reds of years before the dawn of the them theT theP
m Christian era It was being betn celebrated celebratedwith celbratlllwith
T with considerable pomp In many mnn parts purtsof I1rts I1rtsot
of the world worldBefore worldDotore worldfoforo
Before universal unh ersal calendars had been beenthought beenIho beenthought
thought Iho ght of as a remote possibility and andIhe andI andms
the beginning of the year varied as to ton totII todate
n tII I date In almost every part of the world worldthis worldthis worldthis
this first day of the new year was rue recognized rueognlzcd rocognized ¬
ognized as the ono great festival of oftho ottho ofthe
tho twelve months monthsTradition monthsTradition monthsTradition
Tradition tells that Numa who lived livednearly Ihcdnearly ltvedpearly
nearly eight centuries before Christ Christtfc
tfc celebrated a festival that was dedicated dedicatedrk dedicated dedlcnteJrk
rk to Janus on the first day of the month monthracred monthee monthraered
racred to the god On this occasion all allw allItomans allee
ee Romans Joined together to make the theati thon theair
air n Jay 5aya a merry morr one Sacrifices were made made1C m do do3C
to Janus and all mechanics and mon menof month monof
1C of letters began something In line with withtheir withtheIr withIh
th their trades or arts Tho cornerstones cornerstonesve
ve C of buildings were laid new enterprises enterprisesrci
rci were Inaugurated books mid nnl poems poemsivera poemsen
nero oro commenced and tho consuls who whocn whoesi
en had already been elected took their theires theirteals
es esi t teals tealske cats catsIce atske
ke The ancient Greeks began tho year yearr enr enrr
r about abo t the summer solstice or June 21 21Tho 2 2The 21The
The Persians also began their year yearIn
a In n June the Chinese In March and theelf the theAbysslnlans theAbYlIslnlnns
elf 11 Abysslnlans In n August The ancient ancllntI
111 I people p o le of Mexico had a calendar that thatflked thatIIxed thatrn
rn eked tho beginning of the year In Feb Februnry l Febto eb
10 runry runryiln runryIin
iln Early In the history of the Roman Romanhi
hi cople New Years Day was celebrated celebrated1m
1m I nl fn in n January There are traditions of ofic ofae
ic that age that are nr almost ns reliable as asnl nsnl asnl
nl history To say that the > day originated originatedre
re it t that time however would be a mis misj
j I take Long before that period whon whonou
ou the Roman calendar was In such an ana anal anal
a al incerialn condition that tho your oor someul some someul someul
ul
times began in March and sometimes sometimesIn
In April 11r1I this festival was known and andcelebrated amIctlobratod andcelebrated
celebrated celebratedDRUID
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
          <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90059523/1899-12-31/ed-1/seq-7/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>There is one peculiar feature that ac
centuates the happy New Year, which,
paradoxical a» It may sound, will dawn
at midnight this evening. It Is the fact
that quite a respectable number of re
spectable people believe that we are about
to Jump Into ~th<* twentieth century.
It la thia arspeet of the ca.se that has
plunged us lalo gloom. It hasn't occurred
before for a-hundred years, and, while it
cannot be truthfully called monotonous,
it Is. at least, aggravating. If not debili
tating. Whatv "w*' may ask, has a hundred
years of civilisation and delving into book
lore done for im^ how has our improve
ment in mathematics benefited us If at
thlß stage of the world's game, and in
this spirit of the age, wo find men and
women all around us willing to accept
ninety-nine -yoars f o r a century, when
none of them would accept ninety-nine
cents in change, for a dollar -unless the
train was Just starting and they were In
a hurry?
But every cloud has its silver lining.
Beyond the deep gloom of the twentieth
century controversy we can look out
upon something bright and glittering in
the new year about to make its debut.
The old year has been a history-making
epoclj. In the distant future the pes
simistic historian will sit himself down to
an improved typewriting machine and say
things about us, some good, others ran
corous and extremely critical. There are
so many literary people always ready to
carp. Do the best we can, it is impossi
ble to avoid mistakes. The young man
who swore off last New Year's day has,
doubtless, been sworn at at various and
unexpected moments during the 565 days
intervening since then.
Each year it is getting mor« and more
difficult to swear off. At present the
swearing off process contains altogether
too much renunciation of the good things
of life. The luxuries of a year ago are
the necessities of today. Some of your
friends, who do not happen to use the
weed, will log-roll and pull wires to in
duce you to swear off using tobacco In
any form. Yet "you will find trade jour
nals devoted to the tobacco interests
which will readily and editorially prove
to you. from a medical or scientific view
point, that tobacco aids digestion, quick
ens the intellect, and keeps peace in tha
family.
Do you propose to swear off drinking?
One of the picturesque events of the past
year was the appearance of an eminent
professor in an Eastern university who
declared that a few ounces of good whis
ky, taken dally, was not only a food, but
of incalculable benefit to the human sys
tem. Are you contemplating a renuncia
tion of the^ seductions of draw poker?
Within the past six months a Chicago di
vine has declared from his pulpit that all
forms of business were gambling, pure
and simple, and that when the farmer
deposited valuable seed grain in the vlr.
Sin soil, he bet the worth of that grain
on weather conditions, and the problem,
atlcal appearance of chinch bugs, grass
hoppers or weavil, and the Chicago di
vine is backed up, or corroborated— if you
prefer a more euphonious verb— by a New
YoTk clergyman who believes that draw
poker, judiciously played, Is far from be
ing sinful. Without doubt the Judicious
winner will corroborate the New York
preacher.
Now what are you going to do when
confronted by cases like the above?
"Dost thou think because thou art vir
tuous there shall be no cakes and ale?
Yes. by St. George, and ginger shall be
hot r the mouth, too." This Is a precept
as old as Don Quixote and Sancho Panza.
Yet today, on the threshold of a new
year, are we not seriously debating the
question of giving the world, the flesh
and the devil the marble heart, forget
ful of the fact that for so many years in
the past, when we have religiously and
penltentially resolved to lead acetic lives
for a twelve month, the world, the flesh
and the devil have given us the merry ha!
ha! before the first quarter had ex
pired.
Have wo not Biblical writ'for the claim
that there Is ft time to dance and a- time
to sing, a time to make merry with ta
bor and pipe? Surely we can mix pleas
ure with the au!l cares of this life even
if It takes a whole season of golf dissipa
tion to tone up our systems for the se
rious duties of collaring the elusive dol
lar.
The man yrho retains his youth 13 the
young man, and the vivacity of his lift
shall prove It.
There la no use of approaching the
dawa of tomorrow under a
weighty sense of discouragement. Some
literary big wig has solemnly and owl
ishly observed within the past decade
that there was less opportunity nowa
days for the ambitious young man than
when our naLure was young. Bosh! Cir
cumstances are always ready-made and
waiting for the hand of resolve to grasp
them and mold them to the purpose of
the Individual.
And* within a few brief hours the old
year will be a closed book. The record
of our lives for that year will have been
made up and passed over to the Great
Auditor of all earthly accounts. Father
Time. In a few hours 1000 will burst
upon us with all Its glorious possibili
ties. "Ring: out the old, ring in the
new." Let us resolve to cut deeper into
the granite rock of adversity that we
may gain a firmer foothold for the future.
Whatever advancement we have made
during the past twelve months will add
to our momentum In the days to come.
Many will fall and some succeed, and the
young man of patient endeavor is quite
likely to be numbered among the "some."
What has been accomplished In the past
can be multiplied in the future. Human
effort can never run down like a neg
lected clock, for It Is regularly wound
by the magical hand of Ambition. The
coming new year is rosy with promise aa
it Is big with questions of moment. It
Is left to the survivors of the perils of
the past to solve these questions right
or wrong. Is it not the duty of each one
to see that the balance between right and
wrong is in favor of right?
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
          <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1900-01-01/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>LESSONS THE OLD
YEAR TEACHES US
'•At St. Francis Church. Vallejo street an
Montgomery avenue, the New Year was
observed at the evening vesper service
Father McMahon preached the sermon
He said: "My dear people assembled here
together at ,the cull of the Holy Father
We all rejoice for the blessings we have
received in the past and we should also
ask for a renewal of the blessings In the
future. The new year should remind us
that we are only here for a short time
It is certain that we all must die. and we
shall then be judged for our good and bad
deeds. It is appointed that we must die
The patriarchs lived for over a hundred
years, but even they were mortal. So
will all the. future generations die. The
church bell tolls for our friends, but who
can tell how soon will thd same bell toll
for us. God has mapped out our lives and
the time f hen he has decided to call na
The man who laughs and says 'Eat drink
and be merry' may be the first one called
We may ask ourselves, shall IRo wh ill r
am walking on the street? Shall I recpfv*
the sacraments? * receive.
"We cannot answer these question*
But it will help us in our life, if as we say
our evening prayers we study ourselv%
and rind out if we are prepared On th*
eve of the nineteenth century let' unmake
new resolutions to lead better lives xvt
may not know which of us may soon ri*»
who is now sittlmr In this churchThS
young as well as the old are just' as li
able to get the death summons."
At the close of the sermon and th* bene
diction, a solemn Te Deum was sung by
the choir. The choir was composed of-
Sopranos, Miss Ina Collins. Miss Dowllnsr'
Miss Paullissen and Miss Madden: altos'
Miss M. Foley and Miss L. V . Lautin :
tenor. .W. A. Schmidt, and basso, li
Riley. ; ~*
VOLUME liXXXVn — 3S T O. 32.
"To fcirn and to his methods we owe the
great campaigns in favor of religious
liberty carried on by Montalembert in
France and Windthorst in' Germany.
The result of these campaigns was to
•prove to the** world that the ancient
church had, like the eagle, renewed 'her
youth. Her children were as devoted as
ever, her influence as potent, her doc
trine as Inspiring. Compare the con
dition of the church In Europe in the
year ISOO with her condition now, on the
threshold cf the year 1900. Then she .lay,
like the temple, desolate. The" Gentiles
trod her ruined courts "and. the [sacrifice
one knows how much further the weary
pilgrimage may go or when the soul may
pass to the master. Our joy should not
permit us to lose sight of our spiritual
welfare or to forget to look back and from
the lessons and mistakes of the past pre
pare ourselves for the future. Time ob
literates- many things. The deeds of our
greatest heroes are forgotten, and there
Are • but few true hearts that beat re
sponsive to their names. Their memory
has perished with the day. To us all that
remains of the. past is our accountability
for sin and our reward for our sacrifices.
"This is the time for resolutions for
.' -.."As- we. are about- to, pass • over the
threshold of another year and Into, a new
century it behooves us to: look back and
see: what use, we haveinade of the time
that .has.- gone, . and . from what we find
form , strong, resolutions for our better
ment during the year/to come. Another
year, has passed and another is now be
fore; us. " ; Whether it : will be for us or
against us, for weal or for woe. Is for you
to determine...- Another year is coming on,
during, which*,; maybe,- there are some
among us who are doomed to destruction.
Time^ls l ithe, gift of God.. Every minute,
every; hour, every day, every year comes
in Maryland . and Pennsylvania, a few
French missionaries with the Indians In
the West, the ruined pueblos of the
southwest and the chain * of: missions
along the Calif ornian coast. In a hundred
years we have not only, kept pace Lwith
the growth of population, but we ' have
outstripped It. We have 'met prejudice
arid persecution, but they fought against
us : in vain. In the ; beginning we were
despised and .hated, then we were feared
and ; . hated; 'now. men wonder at us, but
hate: us none: the. less. The Catholic has
his position In, American life too secure
.to-be. ever- seriously menaced, and. the"
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
          <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1900-01-01/ed-1/seq-10/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>LIEUTENANT FRED L. ESOLA.
county of San Francisco. It has been
known for some time that Mr. Esola was
in high favor with the Mayor and The
Call has been informed by responsible
people, who were either directly or indi
rectly Interested, that in the formation
of the Police Commission his appointment
was a large consideration. In fact, so
firmly convinced was Mayor Phelan that
Mr. Esola would be the right man for the
place that he made his appointment the
test of eligibility and those who expressed
themselves as antagonistic failed to find
their names among the lucky ones wfien
the announcements were made.
Almost at the eleventh hour one of
San Francisco's prominent legal lights
was called In and proffered a commission
ership by the Mayor and apparently only
the formality of his acceptance stood be^
tween him and his appointment. At the
last moment he was asked if he had any
objection to Mr. Esola as Chief of Police
and replied that he had. "Why," asked
Mayor Phelan. "He is a better man than
Lees, is he not?
"I do not think he is," was the reply-
Lees has had long experience and is still
capable and I do not see why he should
be displaced." Mayor Phelan then ex
plained his Interest in his candidate by
saying: '
When Mr. Hearst was out here the last
time he expressed great admiration for
Lieutenant jEsoia and asked me as a per
sonal request to make him Chief of Police
if the opportunity should arise. The op
portunity Is here and I am strongly In
clined to accede to Mr. Hearst's request."
The Mayor's explanation, however, did
not serve to convince Lee's champion and
he left the ottlce. His name also failed
to appear among subsequent announce
ments.
The newly appointed Commissioners are
non-committal when asked as. to their
preference tor the Chief's ofllce, but to
friends all but one of them has expressed
himself as favorable to Lieutenant
Esola's appointment. Mr. Biggy has made
no secret of his loyalty to the Mayor's
choice, William Thomas has said nothing,
but is understood to be of the same mind
and George W. Newhall is known as a
warm friend of Mayor Phelan ana ready
to lend his vote to Esola's case when the
commission shall come together to consid
er the matter. Dr. W. F. McNutt has
said that he would not vote for Esola,
but despite the doctor's denial It is posi
tively known that he will be on hand
when the can comes.
Of the four candidates who at first as
serted their claims to the office only
Esola remains. .Captain Wlttman retired
early in the nght; Colonel W. P. Sullivan
declares that he never was a candidate
and Chief Lees gave up the fight on Sat
urday. Early in the day the Chief was
made aware of the personnel of the new
commission .and calling an expressman he
loaded all of his personal. effects and pri
vate records Into a dray and had them
taken to his home. Lees Is as confident
as are others as wise In politics that
Esola Is to be his. successor.
As stated above, The Call unhesitating
ly predicts that Lieutenant Fred Esola
will be the next Chief of Police. If the
prediction be true The Call hopes that he
will prove a good man In the place. It
will support him In his efforts to do right,
and will not hesitate to crltcize him if he
be ever at fault.^BßS -. -;c
twentieth century. Pirwt, the latxw erne»- ¦
tlon. It is a pity the present century should
close with selfishness so swaying the heart*
of men. There is a mighty battle between .
the rich and poor. .' ' ¦ • ¦ • ¦ . ;
At the beginning of this century ther« .'•
were but two millionaires In this country. .
To-day there are 404 T. The other question
Is that of settling country disputes between
nations. It is a burning shame that in th«
closing years of the nineteenth century war
is raging In the world and is carried out by
the two most highly civ Mr-ed nations on the .
face of the globe. America and Great Brit
ain are to-day settling disputes by the
bloody sword, ft is a sad picture. Oh,
when wil! we learn that the sword must
jrlre Way to the scerter of Christ? The .
twentieth century must answer. _.¦¦'¦- ..._'.'.
Rev. E. A. Woods In his sermon last
night to the members of the First Bap
tist Church said: •••:.'
"On this last day of the year if we
listen we shall hear a voice saying to
us. "Trust not to your own . wisdom, but
consult with God. The past of life Is
gone, but the present is ours. Shall w«
make next year bettor than the past has
been? Let us commence to-day."
If Rr the old year glides away,
A weary wraith in the wind and the- cold.
We could but begin in the New Year's day
A clf-an. new life, and could drop the old—.'.
¦ What blessings untold would to us be given— ¦
. Scarce in our hearts would be room for
heaven.
Rev. Philip Coombe, pastor of the
Richmond ¦ Congregational Church,
preached yesterday morning on "What
Has the Nineteenth Century Bequeathed
to the Twentieth?" In part he said:. :
The nineteenth century has led us out of th«
dark regions, of atheism aJongr the cold road of
scientific investigation into the pleasant places
of intelligent faith in God, and enterprising: en
deavor for bringing . alt ; the nations of the
earth into the s&ir.e ropdly heritage. How,
then, can we best undertake twentieth century
responsibilities? .
For generations the unborn did with few ad
vanta«f a. <5M In the face of great obstacles,
did In poverty, unappreciated, almost unknown,
their worth unrecognized, until they w*nt to
heaven and heard God say to them each, "Well
done, good arid faithful servant; enter thou.in
to the joy ot thy Ix»rd." We must undertake
th» wr>rk that la nearest to our hand and do
It as well and bravely as if God and the whole
world were looklnsr on. ¦' ' .
We may do this by realizing- what the«» r»-
FjyinEib'.lltles axe. We are. prone to forgetre
pponelbllltles In the enjoyment of great privi
leges. :. ¦"•:•:¦ ,*>:•'.>< • • .
Webster Invoked a curre ur-?n himself one*,
if he ever forgot what hi*' father did for his
education. May we, .every one of us, say:
• - I>et my r!prht han<! forget Its cunning If I ever
foriret my nineteenth century benefactors." We
ought to remember. .;' ¦' ¦¦¦;'¦'.-'.
All the available police officers In the
city were on duty on Market street from
il:30 o'clock last night until after the new
year was ushered in. Captain Spillane no
tified the men who usually report off duty
at midnight to remain on their beats until
32:30 o'clock, and the relief watch was
ordered out half an hour earlier than
usual. All the officers on the side streets
were also Instructed to patrol Market
street and assist in keeping the crowd In
check.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
          <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84020274/1900-12-31/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>
          ST. LOUS TO GLADLY
WELCOME NEW CENTURY.
Plan to Illuminate the City To-Night Will Probably Be Carried
Out Midnight Church Services Watching Parties
World's Fair Meeting.
The departure of the Nineteenth and tho
dawn of the Twentieth Century w 111 be cele-
brated by all St. Loulsans at 12 o'clock to-
night In a manner which will be appropri
ate to the epoch that it marks In the city's
history. The passing century saw the birth
of the Louisiana Purchase Celebration
movement, and the advent of the Twen
tieth will probably witness the completion
of the 15,000,000 World's Fair Fund, which
Is to insure the success of the greatest
celebration tho world has ever witnessed.
All the committees which have been
working hard to complete the fund are
ready to announce the success of the un
dertaking to-night.
The Republic's plan of greeting the new
century with an elaborate illumination in
church, store, dwelling and street has met
with approval from all the leading busi
ness men, members of the Merchants' Ex
change and kindred organizations, city of
ficials and citizens, and it Is believed that
the new year's arrival will tee the city bril
liantly lighted. 4
"The Republic's Idea of a general Illumi
nation Is a good one." said City Treasurer
Bcudder. "It will. Indeed, be a grand sight
It every house In the city Ik illuminated."
MAY complete:
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85054468/1901-01-01/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>THS DAWN OP THE NB7r CENTURY
iX
0 THE CUBAN POSTALvIEAUDS
Tjo Senate May Not Bo Furnished
With Desired Information
ieeretnry Itoot Not IIIijiohciKIo Com
ply Willi Revolution Calllne for
the Iteliorl Submitted lofjhe Wlir
lJeiiiirlnicnt by Auditor Lnwhhf
t
Senator Bacons resolution adopted by
the Senate shortly before ChaBrmas call
ing upon the Secretary of Wagfdr a copy
of the report made by AudtSsr Lawshc
giving the result ot his inspigtlon of the
accounts of civil and militarVofficers In
Cuba will probably not be ccoiplied with
by th War Department f
Secretary Itoot is ofposedfcito1 sending
the report to the Senate an has so In
formed the President He explained yci
negotiations with the Danish Foreign Of
fice
The wishes of the Inhabitants of tho isl
ands In regard to the change has already
been expressed a plebiscite having devel
oped that a majority was favorable to
transfer from Danish to American con
trol The treaty in course of preparation
provides for the sale to the United States
of all the islands St Thomas St John
and St Croix
FOHGOT THE MABCH 0 TIME
IliKht of the OivnerM of the Nine
teenth Century MnKilTliie
LONDON Dec 31 The proprietors of
the Nlnetcenlh Century Magazine have
apparently forgotten that the march of
time was making the present title of their
periodical inappropriate and consequent
ly lacking the foresight to register the
title Twentieth Century which has
been snapped up tho magazine will bs
heniefortli entitled the Nineteenth Cen
tury and After
On the title page will bo reproduced a
Janus like head adapted from a Greek
coin of Tenedos by Sir Edward Former
terday that If It was sent l47the Senate Presided or the Itojal Academy The family and childrens rarty at
it would become public property and lie hcail which looks to the left is that of a There was a magnificent tree I
m rnnallnr i fnr th lat Interests Iearoeu man uraiiBwieui it in ituiau
--
of the public service that tbe report be
made public pending the trkh of the ac
cused postal officials eourse
will be followed In replying to the Senate
resolution has not --
The rr
Presi
mltted
recomr
fused i
It m
mininnlc 1c tin fitritf VIV fin th nthr lllS
side looking to the riEht is the head of
0u mocii m strongly condemned by
both the Dutch and English Loyalists
It Is reported that a number of ren
sational arrests including that ot a
former member of the Cape Cabinet and
the editor of a leading Afrikander Bond
newspaper are Impending The charge
against tbese men will be sedition
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
          <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85054468/1901-01-01/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>LONDON Dec 31 The proprietors of
the Nlnetcenlh Century Magazine have
apparently forgotten that the march of
time was making the present title of their
periodical inappropriate and consequent
ly lacking the foresight to register the
title Twentieth Century which has
been snapped up tho magazine will bs
heniefortli entitled the Nineteenth Cen
tury and After
On the title page will bo reproduced a
Janus like head adapted from a Greek
coin of Tenedos by Sir Edward Former
terday that If It was sent l47the Senate Presided or the Itojal Academy The family and childrens rarty at
it would become public property and lie hcail which looks to the left is that of a There was a magnificent tree I
m rnnallnr i fnr th lat Interests Iearoeu man uraiiBwieui it in ituiau
--
of the public service that tbe report be
made public pending the trkh of the ac
cused postal officials eourse
will be followed In replying to the Senate
resolution has not --
The rr
Presi
mltted
recomr
fused i
It m
mininnlc 1c tin fitritf VIV fin th nthr lllS
side looking to the riEht is the head of
0u mocii m strongly condemned by
both the Dutch and English Loyalists
It Is reported that a number of ren
sational arrests including that ot a
former member of the Cape Cabinet and
the editor of a leading Afrikander Bond
newspaper are Impending The charge
against tbese men will be sedition</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85034438/1901-01-01/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>PX.KNTY OF V.'OItK.
One of ihe most satisfaetory thlngs in
conncction with present dondltions Is the
fact that there is plcnty of work for all
who deslre to labor. There are industries
on every harid, requiring both skilled and
unskilled labor, and ns a rule, the wages
pald are regarded as satisfaetory.
Many hundreds are cmploycd in the
railroad improvemenls and at the fac
lories. A new and increasing -;nterprlse,
which has given cmploymcnt to a large
number, is the "W. R. Trigg Shipbtiildlng
Company.' Thls corporatlon is steadlly
cnlarging its plant, and the prospects are
that the demand for workmen there wlll
steadily increase. ;
Taken all in all tlie conditlons here have
nevcr been more satisfaetory. A glance
through the columns of thls issue of The
Times will deppnstrate ^that the State
and city are entering on a"new year and
a new century with the prospect that be
?fore it ls many years old Richmond will
wear the title, "Leading city of the South."
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1901-01-01/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>"During this century, we have, on a whole,*
moved upward; I hope- we shall continue
so to move.*' but whether we do or- not 1
will ultimately depend upon whether on
the average the Individual • -man shows
Mark Twain cent the following charac
teristic greeting: "I bring you the state
ly matron named Christendom, returning
bedraggled, besmirched and dishonored
from pirate raids In Klaochau, Manchu
ria. South Africa and . i the Philippines,
with her bouI full of meanness, her pocket
full of boodle and her mouth full of pious
hypocrisies. Give her soap and a towel,
but hide the looking-glass/'
Sir Henry Irving wrote as follows: "I
have the deepest sympathy with the ob
jects of the American Red Cross Society,
and I Join with you in the hope that the
new century, which will soon dawn upon
us, will be laden with more blessings of
peace that the whole* world craves."
Lord Roberts, under date of November
9 writing from Johannesburg. South Af
rica, says: "The present century has
brought with it many discoveries Which
have done much to alleviate the miseries
of suffering humanity. I pray that the
coming century may be equally produc
tive of a further progress In matters that
conduce to the health, happiness and well
being of all people."
These words of Kngland's great soldier
struck a responsive chord in the hearts
of all who heard the message last night,
and it was greeted with round upon round
of applause.
Band played a number of patriotic airs
during the evening. Camille d'Arvllle-
Crellin sang a number of songs, and the
choirlstefs of the Mission Good Samari
tan rendered carols and hymns. Tho
musical portion of the programme in
cluded Hother Wismer, Miss Marie Wil
son. Mrs. Arnold. Mr. Young, Mrs. Wal
ter Fonda and Miss Moroney.
The various speakers of the evening
dwelt upon the wonderful developments
of the dying century and hoped that the
twentieth century would see ptlll greater
advancements. Mayor Phelan made a
stirring address, eulogizing the noble
work of the Red Ctoss Society, and his
words were rewarded with hearty ap
plause.
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
      <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030193/1901-01-01/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>THE TWENTIETH CENTURY
THE AGE OF THE COMMON MAN
e
A IHJW century tlic in v century
Wind does it mean tll yon Why tI > you salntn its dawn so
i
cheerfully so hopefully i
I VIIAT Dili Vine centuries have pasted since the I
I run MV m I
Tlllll MKA 1 world llnil measure tiniu from tin birth of
I TO VOIf kHIS lias paid jiny especial nttention to the I
1 mure numeral marking the change of century II
The lnt time was the Iarl 1000 Jhen all Christendom hoicvce
that tin period for the end of time hxed in tin Milile had ee > mo uml I
lliat tin millennium was to begin During that entire year people ol
all classes and eondit daily and hourly expected tin appearance
oft III angel who would and with one foot on the hind and one foot
on the sea and herald the reign of lienven upon earth the reign of
peace and justice
Xinu eiiiiiirics and again the world that progroes notes n
numeral tin Twentieth Onliirv with expectation
Why i
For answer we mu > t look back over the century that has just
pllssed
ladMoiie oner aid that irhn were asked to nm up the NMne
teenth Century ilia phrase he would sav that it was
IJXJIAXD MK
That is in the Xineteenih Century iiian prone upon the earth
oadeil with the chilins of menial and phvMcal tyranny wherewith
i i i ignorance and superstition had bound him
IIISTOMS staggered lo his feet and began to shake off
KIMtilt J I i i i > i
1 In shackles one by one
II 1111
MKTIITII What is the meaning of all these ma
nIII Il T terial wonders of the past century What is
i
the deeplying ipiiiicanre of steamship nnd I
railway telegraph and elcutrie light the harnessing tenm and
electricity tn rner over land and son hearim comfort and enliphten
nienl and aspiration into the remotest place to the humblest per
sons1
1ntil this century institutions ruled everywhere The king
wn no 11 4 the > lave of thee inrtitutioin than the peasant The
individual man win nothing an unidentified atom Some of thcse
nt unit were labelled king others prince others burgher other <
peaant lint not one of them over thought Jot theV great thought
when lie wa live year old and ran to lab mother shouting
Mmier Mutter ieh bin uin Ich Mother Mother I am
Mil II
IIA
All were regarded as and regarded themselves as part of the
machine
Today how different
Science lni come And wift as the lightning she tamping
upon each of thee atom an individuality i = < breathing into each of
them a enneitiiisne s of identity iniM > rtancc dignity a concious
ness of the posihiliticf of individual achievement
Tin XinetitKtli Century IIIH been paving the way to make of
the Twentieth Century
1 1 The guof the Common Man
j HAM TO TIM v t Mntt s > llot n istititioii3 not to
AlilOI Illl i
I COMMOM MAM I fashs and order aim ranks belongs the rwcn rt
> tieth Centur
It helongs to the Coiuinon Man to you with your stout heart
ind your willing and capable hands and your actives eager brain
ind your SPIIM of the equal rights of all meii
What is the watchword this new day
It isYOU
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045211/1916-03-31/ed-1/seq-20/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1958-11-09/ed-1/seq-219/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/45043535/1900-01-01/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>With the issue of this first number we call upon our
readers and friends to continue us their generous support
0 and good will, by early sending in the price of their sub
scription, by making the Indian Advocate known among
their acquaintances and informing us of all such news that
may be of interest to the readers of our review in any of
the lines just mentioned. In this expectation, we wish to
all a thrice happy New Year 1900; and may the first year
of this Twentieth Century be a prosperous one for the work
we carry out for God's greater honor, by the advancement
and education of the Indian tribes, and the settlers in the
Twin Territories that offer such a fertile field to missionary
zeal and Catholic apostleship.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88056017/1899-12-02/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86091142/1899-12-29/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn94054571/1914-05-16/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn93050700/1899-12-26/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86090500/1900-01-15/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90051548/1899-12-28/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>WITH CHARITY FOR ALL-1900
And » Happy New Year Greeting and
Many Return* of ttie Same.
During the 20th century. We return
many thanks for the favors bestowed
upon us the past year. Hoping that all
will be blessed with peace, plenty and
prosperity during the New Y’ear, we
respectfully solicit a continuance of your
patronage.
Very respectfully yourj,
The Central Shoe and Clothing Co.
Central City, Dec. 28, 18913.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86090500/1900-01-10/ed-1/seq-1/ocr/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>

  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-wwi-tanks</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045211/1916-09-19/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>FIRST PICTURE OF DESTRUCTIVE BRITISH "TANK" WAR CAR
Above is a diagram of the armor and gun equipment which, it is "'clieved, the British have mounted on the
Holt motor tractor, of which a recent photograph is reproduced here. Thugh the British are giving credit
to various officials for the invention, the actual tractor is an American product, manufactured at Peoria, 111.
About 1000 have been shipped to the British Government. Their most striking feature is the double cater
pillar wheels at the rear, which run on jointed rails fitted on the inside of corrugated belting. The 18,000
pounds of weight is so balanced that the heavy front -wheel can bo "Jerked" into tho air so as to cross an
obstacle, just as a rider pulls up the head of his horse to cross, a ditch or fence. Its makers say it is quite
possible for tho machine to get astride a trench and enfilndc its occupants on both sides by machine-gun fire.
The tractor develops 120 horsepower and can attain a speed of about ten or twelve miles an hour.
SOFIA, Sept. 19. The repulse of all
'llicd attacks around the Greek town
E cf Fiorina was announced by the Bui
lt itaritn War Office today.
El liulgarian troops aro continuing ineir
hdrancc against the Rumanians in the
Dolrudja and have captured the Black
f3ea port of Mangalia, twenty-three
', jii!c. south of Constanza.
BERLIN. Sent. 19. The Germans
stave surrendered trenches to the Brit-
If'U east of Ginchy and north of Com-
i , DUt nave rcpuisca rrencn auucHs
jrWr Bolloy and Vermandovillers, south
KM the Somme, It was pfficiallyan-
uH-uiiced today. '
SAI.ONlCA,-Sept 19.
rbfan. Russia., and French troops have
lri- the entire right wins of the "Bui-
tltrlat army out of Greece across the
Swbl frontier and are pressing on toward
lorost'. accordlnc to cftlclal advices re-
i'ttl't- here today.
Rte ....Izlne their Inability to hold
(Uonastlr against the strong forces pursuing
Jtbelr beaten troops, the Bulgar leaders are
IMld to be evacuating that city, part of
th I.nlgarlans having already been with-
ittn toward Uskub.
1$, 'Tin capture of Fiorina by the Entente
fAlltc Is rerlously menacing tho Ilulgar
Tftn'; and French bfllcers today predicted
jtiwti e entire enemy front uould be drawn
Uatlf wcrnl miles to prevent Its being
8nUd from tho west. '
French and Russian troops axe engaged
Ijflth the Hulgars near Kenall, on Serbian
iterritory. Virtually all the territory con-
SwierM by tho Bulgarian right wing In the
lltcent Invasion of Greece has already been
s recaptured by the Serbs, French and uus-
If.
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85058396/1916-10-21/ed-1/seq-19/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85058396/1916-10-21/ed-1/seq-19/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>WITHOUT a moment's Indecision, Houseman llj
turned his machlno broadsldo before the 111 HHH
opposing guns and started over the intervening Hi BHh
000 yards for tho crippled member' of hit HI HBHH
charge. At wltat seemed to him a snail's pace, W "HBHH
ho crossed tho Ilrc-rldden Hold slowly, but Hi ( HBHH
with the appalling surety of the tractor "tank." '
Tho approaching flro of the batteries mounted H ' IHHrJ
on Houseman's car drovo back tho Germans Hi HBHH
who wore about to swarm on to tho stricken Hi
tractor. And ns Houseman blazed his way up HI IHlllH
to tho silent machine, tho Germans retired to ' H
eafety from the gun flro of his crew. Jaj
Amidst tho din of battlo ho could got into no Jh Hlllfl
communication with the unharmed men of the MB) ! Hllll
other tractor. How badly thoy had beon bit HJ jH
ani what their condition was ho could not an- ijfBj , jH
certain, but a plan for rescuing them and the jttrl
machine very quickly occurred to HoiiEoman. Ml
Ho sto.rtod his machine around tho comrade ijlj sftyjfJ
"tank" In ns narrow a olrcle as It could ncgo- 'HI HBHH
tlnto AVIth tie guns blazing forth at the Ger- jnjj
1 mane, and with their machlno guns and rifles IH1 HlllJ
antwerlng haughtily but fruitlessly, Houseman's Hi
command crossed in front of the other car and IHj IHlllJ
Atcppcd for a baro momont, forming a sort of T. R
In thnt second, Housoman had raised the ar- H
mrrod trap and slipped out bf his car and j tk
3 nrcund to tho roar of the other. He carried a IHJ HHH
sturdy grappling chain, which, with utter dls- '' HHJ
regard for tho bullets cutting the air about him, !
1 ho meant to fasten to tho wounded tractor. H
1 Meanwhile his own machine trundled around V
t until It reached tho spot whoro Housoman was HMbJ
working. He had fastened the chain on the Hj HH
1 hind ond of tho "dead" tractor and was Just B JhHh
ready whon tho machlno relumed to him.
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1917-07-08/ed-1/seq-43/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Seven French tanks in action. After a heavy artillery fire to silence the
enemy's guns, the mobile forts are advancing to the attack: the foremost
one leaping an abandoned trench. An idea of the size of these monsters
is given in the picture to the right. As it is, the present French tank it
smaller, though much more effective, than the first unwieldy British
invention. The paint waves on the tanks are the work of the Camouflage
Corps, whose skill is such that at a distance the object treated seems to
blend with the landscape. Several hundred prominent American artists
recently formed an association for Camouflage to aid our own army.
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1917-08-12/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TANKS'RANK FIRST AMONG
NEW INVENTIONS
"Gasoline cavalry" Is the name be-
vtowed upon the armed caterpillar
tractors of Trance and England by a
writer la the current (sane of xht
BeJenUfle AmtHcu. watch contains a
hljhly iatereatlna- article concrnUa
those awkward.looklns but hlchlr
Zectire enainea of destruction.
The "tank." aliBousm ortsl&attna In
Encland, has reacaed 1U hlg-best de
vtlopmeat at the hands ol French
mechanicians and deilg-nsra. As the
Scientific American correspondent
points out, the novelty of the huxe
Iron Juggernaut, with Its machine
(runs and lt "thousand legs," appeals
to the .Frenchman's lrrepreealble sense
of humor and enabled him to develop
the Idea with remarkable alacrity and
dexterity.
The tank called a "mttal rhin
oceros" by the grinning pollu Is the
most remarkable and efficient piece of
mechanism which the war hae devel
oped, with the possible exception ot
the submarine. The latter, however
was well oi Its way toward practical
potentiality before hoatilltles began.
so the tank hae a clear title to the
honors.
The following excerpta from the
Scientific American article will pro
vide a good idea of the manner in
which the French englneere adopted
the British Invention and turned 1
to good account:
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89066315/1918-03-30/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TRACTOR
EVOLVESJNTO TANK
From Farm to Battlefield Is
Story of American
Invention -
USED BY BRITISH
Effective at the Somme and
at Cambrai Conserve
Lives of Soldiers
And the worm turned from a harm
less farm tractor Into the tank the
fighting machine most dreaded by the
Germans It was the caterpillar which
gave Benjamin Holt of California
the idea for a tractor which could pass
over rough ground and through mar
shes and deep sand And it was the
ability to do this which caused the
British to introduce it into warfare
The tanks are movable forts which
demolish barbed wire entanglements
go over shell holes and trenches go
j through brick walls and smash down
trees They do their best work when
going at the rate of only two and one
half miles an hour and their maxi
mum speed is only four These lum
bering monsters are 23 feet long 9
feet wide 8 feet high and weigh about
25000 pounds with the heavy armor
plate which covers them They are
equipped with field guns which are
fired as they approach the enemy
Machine gun bullets three inch shells
and rifle bullets have no effect on the
armor of the tanks It is only the
heavy artillery which can stop them
and this is ineffective if the tank gets
close enough because the big guns
cannot be depressed so as to make a
square hit
Tanks have no wheels but crawl on
corrugated belts Each side is under
independent control so that the ma
chine can be turned around in its own
length The center of gravity is far
back and not more than a foot and a
half above the ground
Tractors were used as trucks early
in the war but it was not until the
battle of the Somme that they were
used as tanks In the big British
drive before Cambrai the tanks drove
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045211/1918-04-02/ed-1/seq-7/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>IN BATTLES OF MARCH
Big Tanks, 45 Feet Long, Have 3-Inch Guns and Can
Be Sealed Up in Gas Zone Two Other
Types Seen in Battle
Uttuua, April '.'. j Ion. The land cruisers aro forty-flvo
A dispatch fiom French headquarters fcet lne. thirteen feet wldo and thirteen
... feet liiRh. The speed of tlio Herman
J tanks cairlei from four nnd one-half to
"Although tho toldlers believe that , nn,0 niul one-half miles per hour. The
enemy tanks did not participate in tho armament Is believed to consist of a
llrst German shock, It U ceitaln that Miovtened 77 inlllmeter (three-Inch) gun,
tanks actually took pdrt In tho opera- machine guns and a flame thrower. The
tlons. The fcoldlcrs failed to see them, i latter Is an innovation, which limit add
because. Instead of accompanying tho ' considerable efllclcney to tho tank In
Infantry waves, the tanks advanced lHtcr clearing trenches, owing to tho capacity
with specialist ttoop.i to destroy islets ! of tho tanks to carry uscrvco of corn-
of resistance holding out after the Ger- bu&tiblo liquid
man hordes submerged the llrltif h main . . , . .
defence ( "" ls understood that tho Germans
"It Vknown that the enemy has tanks ''"" introduced a number of Improve
of three classes. The llrst olaba con- Imerts. Including heavier protection
slits of repaired captured tanks from the against rliells and a device, enabling tho
Cambral battlo and tanka mauufactuied crew to closo tho tank hcimctlcally when
according to tho model of tho Hrltlsh . traversing an area of gas.
machine. Tho second type Is a German 'German tanks aro commanded by
model, smaller than the Hrltlsh. but majors. Tho onkcrs arc volunteers, and
swifter, better armed and more heavily tlic men motor specialists, gunners, and
aimored. Tho third typo 3 a lanJ machine gunners.
cruiser or large model tank. i "In attacks the tanks nre designed to
"Tho swift tanks are .-aid to be , advance behind tho second or third wave
twenty-six feet long, ten feet wide and of Infnnlrv, while detachments of ln
cloven feet high, weighing ten metric ' fantry cover their flanks '
I Teutoni Tenteranno di Inva-</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88084272/1918-07-19/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Washing-ton. D. C, July H- Offi
cers wearing- the latest tank model on
their collars as Insignia, are busy re-
cniiUng; husky Touna- Americans to
man the land ships of the United
States army. The tank corps is the
newest branch of our rapidly expanding-
land force, but It is not going; to
be the smallest, nor yet the least im
portant. The tank corps came Into existence
In February as a small part of the
engineer corps. Within a month It
was advanced to the status of an in
dependent corps of the. army, its im
portance manifested by the heavy at
mosphere of secrecy which surrounded
its development.
Treats 'Km Return.
The tank unit Is popularly known
as the treat 'em rough corps," and It
includes men from almost every trade.
business and profession. Soldiers of
fortune, bank presidents, and mechan
ical engineers Inhabit the same tank
and the same bunk at the training
camn. Collece men and mechanical
engineers have been enlisted in large
numbers because tank corps orncers
believe that Tnen highly trained along
technical lines and men of good edu
cation are needed If the tank corps is
to be a success.
Men from Europe and all parts of
the United Statea loin the corps. An
American engineer from Java and an
other American from Kussia aroppea
into the recraitine office at Washing-'
ton the other day. Both had come to
America to enlist as "tankers and
had crossed on the same ship, neither
knowing the other's destination.
Xetbeds Change Frequently.
In tank fighting, as in trench war
fare, methods are constantly chang.
lng. Tanks are now being used in
making trench raids and are proving
lust as efficient In this work aa In
tearing open barbed wire and locating
the enemy with well aimed ballets
and shells.
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1918-08-18/ed-1/seq-26/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE TANK llOAD TO VICTORY OPENED
How a New
Weapon Has
Helped Make It
Possible to Turn
Back the Ger?
man Tide
America Hides
Her Gigantic
Plans for New
Steel Cavalry
To Be Ready for
Big Offensive
By Theodore M. Knappen.
Washington, August 17.
TANKS are now the thing in
military circles.
Awhile ago it was air?
planes that were going to
win the war so far as it is te be
won in actual conflict, but now it is
tanks.
Men from every other arm of the
military service are turning now to
the tanks. Majors, captains and
lieutenants are giving up their com?
missions in other services in,order
to enlist as privates in the "tanks."
Word has come back through the
army channels of what one officer
says and writes to another, that
tanks will win this war as artillery
won Napoleon's wars and as the
British long-bows won in the Hun?
dred Years' War.
The word runs that neither gas,
airplanes nor massed artillery will
l>e counted the epochal innovation of
this war,x but that the honor will
be reserved for tanks. Even the
haughty airmen are beginning to
think that the tortoiselike machine
that keeps close to Mother Earth is
the coming conquering instrument of
warfare.
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1918-08-25/ed-1/seq-28/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE TANK CORPS LINES UP ON THE BATTLEFIELD OF GETTYSBURG
Tank Corps Instructors Hand Pick Their
Men for Physical Powers and Fatigue
Capacity From All Ranks
THF news of the "tank" victories
of the last six weeks and the of
ficial assurance that the tank.
once somewhat discredited, is sudden?
ly raised to a high place in the order
of Hun killers was nowhere received
with more joy than among the few
thousand "treat 'em rough" boys in
the American tank camps, Visions of
themselves clattering ahead of the
doughboys and scattering Hun regi?
ments over the landscape became very
real. Those already in training see
themselves as the vanguard of thou?
sands of American tanks leading a tri?
umphant, if bloody, procession to Ber?
lin.
"Give us tanks enough, only give us
tanks enough, and then?oh boy!"
said one of the officers.
And they all feel that way. For the
tank corps is the native home of en?
thusiasm. No man is in it who could
be scared out by stories of privation,
mutilation or sudden death. All are
volunteers, and many, very many, are
men who have given up big jobs, and
even commissions in other branches, to
get inside the clattering monsters.
Many men now in the tank corps have
actually refused commissions in the
corps itself, for the tank officer seldom
rides in the tank, and many of those
who enlist are men whose supreme am?
bition is to see a German machine-gun
nest through the sights of tt-.eir own
Brownings.
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1918-09-14/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Enemy Without Heart
The division comtnanders evidently
ordered the evacuation of their heavy
artillery when the. American artillery's
preparation began at 1 a. m. this,
morning. The barrage began at G a.
m., "like a fiery waterfall upside
down,' as an American officer ex?
plained it. The enemy units fought
without heart and then trailed north?
ward, leaving machine gun nests here
and there to retard the advance.
Before noon the American advance
had met with heavy opposition at two
places?Montmartre Wood, which was
well filled with machine guns, and the
village of Sain Haussant, which was
drenched with artillery tire. An offi?
cer who advanced into Baussant said
it was the hottest fire he ever liad
seen, but, like everywhere else, the
enemy had tied iir.d was giving us a
parting hate from guns far to the
north.
Our line was held up temporarily
until the tire ceased, and then ad?
vanced. The important road centre of
Thiacourt has been seized.
Tanks Surround Thiaucourt
Tanks surrounded Thiaucourt before
the infantry arrived, and when the
first patrols entered the edge of the
town the tanks were sitting around
in a circle waiting for the doughboys.
Thiaucourt has been burning fiercely
in places from our shells since early
in the morning.
The enemy, in spiteful wrath, lias
tilled the village of Fey-en-Hey, west
of Pont-?-Mousson, with mustard gas.
Our leading wave discovered the situa?
tion and deftly piloted itself around
the village, leaving-it. alone until the
fumes were dissipated. American tank
crews shoved themselves ahead, with
courage worthy of the highest credit.
Though some tanks were bogged en
rout?, other.-- worked well ahead of the
infantry, cutting off Boche villages.
guns and prisoners.
In addition to their work at Thiau?
court, the capture of Pannes goes first
to the tanks, who there worked the
same man?uvre.
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89060185/1946-06-06/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1942-08-09/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1951-10-10/ed-1/seq-43/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86075141/1948-02-26/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1958-07-08/ed-1/seq-13/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn91068401/1940-07-16/ed-1/seq-7/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88063294/1944-02-08/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn78002169/1940-07-16/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82014085/1940-10-14/ed-1/seq-24/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
  <text>GASOLINE RATIONED
These descendants of New Zealand's original native race, whose ancestors
i fought British redcoats 8# years ago, now fight for Britain as they did In World War 1.
tank, but in addition there is a
drastic rationing of gas which
keeps the mileage of the private
motorist wittyn narrow limits.
At the start of the war, a com
plete ban on sale of gas was
imposed- Cars disappeared from
the streets as if by magic, caus
ing an astonishing transformation
in the daily street scene. This
was a panic measure, however,
and after a few days was relaxed
to permit the consumption of eight
gallons a month in the case of
smaller cars, and 12 gallons for
larger cars.
Obviously this allowed very lit
tle use of automobiles, so during
the summer holidays, when the
Centennial Exhibition was in
progress at Wellington, all re
strictions were waived. In the
autumn they were re-applied and
have not since been lifted.
Each motorist has a sheet of
coupons colored according to the
horsepower of his car. If, for ex
ample, his ca>- happens to be a
12 h.p. machine of a very popu
lar medium - sized English make,
he has a sheet of yellow coupons,
each of which is numbered, and
entitles him to three gallons. At
present, the pleasure car owner
is allowed to use three of these a
month.
When the coupons are all gone,
the car stays in the garage until
the beginning of the next month.
The greatest act of generosity in
New Zealand today is to give
someone a “petrol coupon."
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1951-05-21/ed-1/seq-12/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>

  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-telephone-invention</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82014896/1876-11-18/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Audible Speech Conveyed Two
MUch by Telcjrrriili.
The Boston Advertiser prints an in
teresting account ot an experiment m
carrying on a conversation by word of
mouth over telegraph wire, made by
Alexander Graham Bell and Thomas
Watson. Telephones were placed at
either end of a telegraph line owned
by th "Walworth Manufacturing Com
nanv. extendiuir from their office in
Boston to their factory in Cambridge
port, a distance of about two miles.
The comnativ's battery, consisting of
nine Daniels cells, was removed from
tlie circuit and another ot ten carbon
elements substituted. Articulate con
versation then took placo through the
wire. The sounds, at first taint and
indistinct, b came suddenly loud and
intelligible. Mr. Bell in Boston and
Mr. "Watson in Cambridge took notes
of what was said and heard, and the
comparison of the two records shows
that the transmission was almost per-
fectlv accurate. Conversation was car
ried on for about half an hour, gener-
ally in an ordinary tone of voice, but
often in whispers. Miie creuit oi tins
important discovery is due to Mr. Bell
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85032573/1877-04-19/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>A Wonderful Invention.
Thrco vears ago the Herald predict
ed that 'the time would come when
the human voice aud musical sound
could be carried long distances over
electric wires, that the prima douna
who sang in New York could be heard
in the music halls of San Francisco.
The Boston Olobeoi Tuesday, has a
dispatch three-quarters of a column
long, which was spoken in Salem and
heard and printed in Boston. Prof.
G. A. Bell, the inventor of the won
derful system, gave a lecture about
the telephone "m Salem, and to illus
trate the working capacity, he had the
operator in Boston give the audience
the news from Washington. Every
word was heard all over the hall, and
the spectators wore so astonished that
thev broke into applause, and, what is
marvellous, the applause was heard
in the Boston office, eighteen miles
away. The Globe says: "Coughing
and singing were then heard, and a
varictv of questions were then asked
from the Salem end, and the news
came fleeting along that the engineers
of the Boston aud Maine railroad had
struck. General Cogswell asked if
trains were running; the answer was
clear and distinct that they were not
at half past five o'clock. Pro. Bell in
troduced the Rev. E. C. BoIle, who
said, 'I shake hands with you cordial
ly in imagination, twenty miles away.'
The Rev. E. S. Atwood akcd, 'Doe
it rain ?' 'It docs not in Boston,' was
Mr. Watson's answer. Pro. Gage, tho
electrician, then spoko through the
telephone, endeavoring to have his
voice recognized. This could not bo
done, as Mr. Watson was not familiar
with tho voice. Mr. Shaje Zsawa was
recognized, Mr. Wattou being perfect
ly familiar with his tones. One of the
assistant in Boston then said that
'Hold tho Forf would bo sung in Bos
ton, and the tunc which followed was
readilv recognized. Prof. Bell closed
his lecture bv briefly staling the prac
tical uses to whit-h ho was confident
the telephone could be applied.
Hearty applause was afforded the lec
turer as he finished, and people flocked
about the stage in large numbers to
more closely examine the wonderful
instrument that had placed them iu
audible communication with people
nearly twenty -miles away. The lec
ture and experiment were an unquali
fied success." New York Herald.
Dr. Potter, of Griffin, Geoigia, ha
a new motor which promises to lay
Kecly's entirely in the shade. With
it, it is said, he can generate electrici
ty in quantities heretofore unparal
leled, and with this he ropoes to de
compose water into a vapor or gas
many times more powerful than steam
which it to be used in propelling ma
chinery. By the same motor he pro
poses to generate a burning gas, which
will make the illumination of streets
and nouses nearly as cheap as moon
shine. An imaginative Irishman has im
proved Upon O.'sian. "I returned,"
says he, "to the hall3 of my fathers by
night, and I found tliein in ruins. 1
cried aloud, 'My fathers, wheie an:
thev?' Ami echo responded, 'Is that
yem
Patrick McClathcry!
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1877-03-31/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE TELEPHONE.
SPEECH AND MUSIC BY TKLF.ilUAril.
flU 00 -i HMT T.MK1N?; BY WIRK?V? H Y AND HOW
THF. SITAKIXG TBUNMtAM ??IT.RATI.S??FNDIMi
Mate TllllOl ?ill HI MAN FI.F.SH?TUB TW?) TKI.
RVHon; s. and THF MS1IBOTHM BB1WBBB TIH.M.
Ob MM of tho hottest ?lays of hint July the t?le
phoue made it* entry into gond eoeiety. BweHeitag
rrowil* bod for a month been el bow in ft ???eh other
beneath tbs flaaSIOOOJ ?if the l.'t ?it? niunl buildings
ao4ssahlngths ?biily Mesotatp that Philadelphie
was a h. t i ity. Ths lim-t opportunity the world
can i'Vi r niter t?test the virtues of blue glass was
then allow.d i<> pas? l?y without experiment. Any?
thing th..t ciihl have hioiIiIkmI Fairuionnt. BBOShiBS
woii'ni a! thai time have been heartily welcomed. A
goodly Boaahst of *< irntiti?* fsolIssBOo addedthob
p.uxpiriiig ?-lh>rts t?? t'nos/? of tho crowd. and nt
temptetl iiioiv minuto studies than the ordinary
stghtBBSte. ThstS was an immenao amount of hard
anil thon.ngli wi-iit?tip work done at Philadelphia
la-st pear, <>i wbiea tin- sissy has neret jrel been
told. Among IM various lorins o? labor laid out for
the JodgBOof AwOVds there waa ?>n?- win? h in its
very nature reqaind kaowlodgO, training, patience,
care? t ''?1 uf ?let? rmiiiing tlio merits of the lastra
nieiits ot precision itml reiearch which were ?-xhib
itiil. It is not at all surprising that the gcnlh nien
who ha.1 this to ?lo fourni it no li^'lit undcrt?kiiig in
the ht-.it ?.ml iniriy of tboos -sMsomflsi r days. Cop*
tainly it was nut un cas, mottet te forin a cm n-c?
lodgment .-ibi.nt a doHeate scient iiie ?-uiiiiivBOOS
O l?le thirty thousand Auterican eJtissos were prj ing
nlei?t tlie pl.-ioc, .staling, pushing, ?u- worse still,
anhing <|in-stioii.s. Tim wnwt of selsnes ?wonted a
i|iiiet boor for their investigations, uinl tin y took it,
Oti the ?luv Of rest.
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82000205/1888-03-19/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THREE OF THE JUSTICES DISSENT
Tlio Claims or DnuvlmiiKli, Orny
nnd tho American Company
Dismissed,
Tho decision in tho Telcphono cases
was read by Associate Justice Blatchford
in the United States Supremo Court to
day. It comprised n very elaborato ro
viow of all tho Inventions of the telephone
which havo como up to claim priority to
tlio discoveries of Bell and tho suits
which have been conducted in the courts
to set asldo tho Bell patent.
Tho court-room was packed before
noon, and tho crowd extended outsido
tho doors nnd across tho corridors.
Justice Blatchford holds that the law
docs not require nt tho timo application
Is made for a patent that thcro shall have
been obtained a hluh deurcoof perfection;
that tho results may not havo boon
entirely satisfactory at first in order that
tho patent may Issuonnd stand against
tlio assaults of others; that the electrical
undulation clfects set forth by Bell in his
application havo been fully attained, and
that tho vibration Is identical to tbo de
scription. It Is first necessary to describe
tho process, then the apparatus. Thoro
was nothing to show that anyone had in
vented an nnparntus prior to that In
vented by Bell, although vibration
by electricity had boon transmitted
wire prior to 18."l.
by
It was left for Bolt to discover tho
principle, nnd this lie adopted and subse
quently perfected. Thcro Is nothing re
? Hiring tho operation of instruments be
oro patent Issues. It is tlio practicability
of the process that Is to ho shown.
It is truo that when Dell got his patents
ho thought tho magnetic process best,
but that docs not provent hint
from using tho electrical pro
cess and attaining tho same results.
Bell discovered tho way to attain tho ro
sults wo havo now in transmitting artlcu
lato sounds by electricity.
A lengthy roviow followed respecting
tho investigations by various electricians
about tho timo of tho issuance of Bell's
patent, and tho conclusion was that no
others haye shown that they over thought
of It.
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn99021999/1899-07-09/ed-1/seq-26/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Birth of the Telephone
The Iron , steel and copper wire used by
one great telephone company In tlio United
Slates of America Mono IB of moro tlmn
sufficient lenRth to loop the earth to tlio
moon. In fnct. If It were i slblo lo make
the connections and to support the 772,989
miles of wlro which the company reports a *
hcltiB tiscd throtiKhont llfi varUnm circuits
on January 1 , 1890 , thrco different wires
could ho stretchul between 0111 plnnot and
lior lunar satellite.
America Is the birthplace of the telephone.
ItH discovery was tnndo generally known
In Philadelphia during June , 187G 100 years
after the sinning of the Declaration of In
dependence and at the Centennial exposi
tion which commemorated thnt event. The
Htory of the Invention of the telephone Is
In many respects tlio mo t marvelous and
Interesting part of thin one > of the world's
wonders.
Alexander Graham Hell , the nonius who
gave It scientific birth , wru born In Edin
burgh , Scotland , In 1817. His father , Alex
ander Melville Hall , was the Inventor of
what Is known as "vlslblo npooth" a sys-
tc'iu of leaching deaf mutes how to Hpeak
by Indicating through visible characters the
cunblnntlon of the vocal ohords ncccss.iry
to produce articulate oumls. To the lifework -
work of his fattier young Hell decided to devote -
vote himself. After a preparatory training
hu cnlcrud London unlvcralty In 18C7 , but
his health failed him and ho left shortly
afterward. In 1870 , In company with his
parents , bo went to Canada.
Realizing Unit tlio United Slates offered
a broader Held for the work ho had In view ,
Young Hell In 1872 came to the United States
and settled In Boston , where ho Introduced
bis father's system of vlslblo speech for
Ido education of deaf mutes. Ho supported
hlnvaolf at llrat with private classes.
Klrxt ICIcclrlc-ul Work.
Meanwhile , and even licforo ho lofl
England , young Hell had commenced cx-
pcrlmcntfl In that branch of physics and
electricity which embraces Hound. To the
task of an Inventor In this line ho brought
it life-long training of a teacher of vocal
physiology a profession Involving a knowl
edge of how to produce and percelvo articu
late sounds. The groundwork of the system
which ho taught consisted In Instructing
iloaf inutea to rccognlzo by sight the mo
tions of the organs which produce speech
and from this to understand the meaning
of spoken words. Ho bccamo an export In
sound , which embraces among Its other
branches that of harmonics. Some tlmo before -
fore ho loft England , Bull , following the
natural bent of his genius , commenced ex
perimenting In harmonics. The art of te
legraphy then afforded an alluring field for
research and , about the tlma ho came to
this country , ho conceived the Idea that
a system of multiple telegraphy might
bo evolved from the principle that
the varlouu chords of a musical In
strument are sensitive to sounds
of different pitch. While In Canada ho
worked out a system of multiple telegraphy
on this basis and on locating In Boston ho
Clarence J. Brake , an eminent physician In
Boston , and on authority on acoustics ,
Bell received from him BO mo encourage
ment for the further prosecution of this
original Idea. His partners , Messrs , Hub-
bard and Sanders , preferred , however , that
the young man should devote himself to the
completion of his system of multiple tel
egraphy , and rather discouraged his seem
ingly Impracticable idea for the transmis
sion of speech by the electric current.
" < ; < < II , " I'rof. ll 'iir > 'M Ailvlcc.
The year of 1875 dawned dark and gloomy
enough on the struggling young Inventor
to have discouraged almost any ono other
than Bell. After he had completed his
system of multiple tc/egrnphy and applied
for his patent , ho was thrown Into con
sternation by llndlng that his title to nn
original Inventor was contested by the dis
tinguished scientist , Ellshn Gray cf Phil
adelphia. He went to Washington to look
after his Interests , and while there called
( n the veteran physicist and electrician ,
Prcf. Joseph Henry , the secretary of the
Smithsonian Institute.
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85038615/1906-04-22/ed-1/seq-41/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>ALEXANDER GRAHAM BELL.
The portrait la from a photograph taken In 1B76. In the building shown In the
background Bell 6poke the first telephone message ever transmitted from
city to city, the wire extending from Boston to Cambridge.
77///? TIE TH BIR THDA Y
OF THE TELEPHONE
How Alexander Graham Bell in March. 1876, Spoke the
First Words Heard Over the Wire?The Outcom of
Experiments Conducted in Boston.
(Bpcelal Correspondence of The Tlmes
DlspatehO
BOSTON, MASS., April 21.-The tele
. phone recently celebrated Its thirtieth an?
niversary, for It was In March, 1S7G, on
the top floor of a boarding house lr. this
city Hint A Graham Bell, as he was
called In those days, spoke to his asso?
ciate, Thomas A. Watson, the first words
ever transmitted electrically by wire.
The occasion was not Intended for a
historical picture. There was none of
the pomp and circumstance that at?
tended the sending of the first message
by telegraph. The two young enthusi?
asts, ono the theorist who evolved the
idea of transmitting articulate sounds
by electricity, the other a practical
electric mechanician, were the only wit?
nesses. A little niore than a year be?
fore Dr. Bell had discovered that his
theory of the telephone was practical,
.?nd since that time they had worked
?iight and day to develop Instruments
. that would make that discovery useful.
:3?ut still they were far from satisfied;
' nnd on this March day, In 1876, they
??vere prepared for further experiments.
.. Watson was listening at the Instru?
ment In his room. Suddenly, almost un
.'?xpccterily, for It Hcemed almost too
Kniarvelous a thing to be true, he heard
'"Bell's voice. ' Faintly, yet distinctly,
V these words camo over the wire to him:
j "Mr. Watson, come here. I want you."
That was the first message ever de?
livered by telephone. Though .Informal,
It was decisive. It lifted telephony
high out-of the realm of theory" and ex?
periment into that of practical realities.
Mr. Hell and Mr, Watson first met-in
1874. At that time Mr. Bell was pro?
fessor of vocal physiology at Boston
"University, and. Mr. AVatson was a
young workman In the shop of a maker
of electrical apparatus at ICO Court
Street, in this city. Mr. Bell visit?e
the shop to have made for him ' samt
apparatus required In his experiment!
with multiple ? telegraphy, ?r the Ide?
of transmitting several telegraph mes?
sages simultaneously without Interfer?
ence with one another; and the work
of constructing this apparatus was as?
signed to Mr. Watson. That Is" how
the two men made the acquaintance ol
each othert
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86069395/1915-02-04/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>A WONDER OF THE AGES.
Man Standing on Atlantic
Coast Can Hear Conversa
tion on Pacific Side.
Less than forty years ago Alexan
der Graham Bell, standing in a little
attic at 6 Exeter Place", Boston, sent
through a crude telephone, his own
invention, the first spoken words ev
er carried over a wire and the words
were heard and understood by his
associate, Thomas A. Watson, who
was at tho receiver in an adjacent
room. On that day, March 10, 1876,
the telephone was born, and the
first message went over the only
telephone line in ' the world a line
less than a hundred feet long. The
world moves a long way ahead in
the span of one man's life. On Mon
day afternoon, January 25, this
same Alexander Graham Bell, sitting
in the offices of the American Tele
phone & Telegraph company at New
York, talked to this same Thomas A.
Watson in San Francisco, over-a wire
stretching 3,400 miles across the con
tinent and part of a system that in
cludes 9,000,000 telephones, connect
ed by 21,000,000 miles of wires.
In that same memorable year of
1876 Dom Pedro de Alcantara, em
peror of Brazil, visiting the first tel
ephone exhibition at our first great
national show, the Philadelphia cen
tennial, picked up the receiver, lis
tened as Professor Bell talked at the
other end of the room, and, amazed
at the wonder of the thing, cried
out: "My God, it speaks." Had
Dom Pedro lived to see the Pan
American exposition he could have
heard Professor Bell talking to him,
not merely from the other end of a
room, but from the other side of a
continent.
The Pan-American exposition it
self, planned to celebrate the com
pletion of the Panama canal and the
joining of the Atlantic and Pacific
oceans, will mark a still closer wed
ding of the east and west. When its
gates are thrown open on February
20, San Francisco will not only be
nearer to New York through a short
ening of its water ways, but will be
in constant and instantaneous touch
with it through the medium of
speech. It is a curious fact, too,
that this second great feat of engi
neering, this other canal, this even
more intimate connection between
the two seaboards has been com
pleted in the same year. Quietly,
almost unnoticed, but steadily and
bravely, while the gigantic steam
shovels were cutting their way
through the earth in the' south, the
engineers of sound and electricity
were weaving their magic webs
through the air and pushing on to
ward the Golden Gate. Their work
has been less spectacular, it has ex
cited little attention, but these men
have met obstacles as Hard to over
come as the Culebra slide, and they
have conquered them. The long-dreamed-of
transcontinental lino is
no longer a dream. New York can
talk to San Francisco.
A DATE TO REMEMBER.
Monday, January 25, 19l6, has
taken its place among the momen
tous dates in the annals of science
and human progress. On that day,
in the presence of groups of promi
nent men on either coast, tho trans
continental telephone wires were
given their first public test, and the
completion of the. line was formarly
celebrated. Distinguished men in
the offices of tho Pacific Telephone
and Telegraph company in San Frari
cisco conversed freely with distin
guished men on the Atlantic sea
board, and one more great chapter
in the history of telephony was fin
ished as Bell, sitting in tho offices of
tho American Telephone and Tele
graph company in New York, talked
to Watson across a continent.
</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86063730/1929-10-14/ed-2/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88078388/1939-01-12/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1937-10-14/ed-1/seq-21/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn98068396/1962-10-19/ed-1/seq-12/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/77618337/1944-11-13/ed-1/seq-45/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
  <text>the Telephone was Bom
ft - " , ii. t 1 1‘ .:■' ~ Win.., me
tinkering with their crude apparatus of wires
and coils. Suddenly, something happened at
Watson’s end of the line.
Bell rushed in, demanding: "What did you do then?
Don’t touch anything! Let me sec!”
The lucky accident of a faulty spring, giving rise to
a current of varying intensity, had provided the
answer to the inventor’s dream! At that moment the
telephone was born.
Alexander Bell had always been obsessed with the
idea of ’’sending the human voice along a wire.” For
three generations his family had been voice specialists.
Before he was 14, he was studying phonetics.
From boyhood, he read omnivorously. In his grand
father’s library were rows of books on acoustics. In
his Boston workshop were many books on electricity.
He read them all.
Thus, by reading, Bell’s genius was fired. Long before
his great discovery, he acquired the knowledge and
AUTOMOTIVE NEWS. NOVEMBER 13. 1944
vision which were to annihilate space and time for
millions...were to add swiftly and immeasurably to the
world’s capacity for productive work.
f 1 1
To Alexander Graham Bell, as to thousands of others who
have left their mark on history, reading was a powerful
inspiration to achievement.
Knowledge is power, and reading is the richest, most
fertile source of knowledge. When you read, you can set
your own pace ... go fast or slow . . . turn back and read
again ... start and stop as you please. Only through the un
hurried eye of the reader can ideas and information he absorbed
fully, in detail.
  </text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1915-02-05/ed-1/seq-32/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85038615/1904-05-08/ed-1/seq-40/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1945-11-04/ed-1/seq-95/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
  <text>It's as
simple as
The original telephone —in
vented by Alexander Graham
Bell in 1876—employed the
same device for both talking
and listening. The carbon trans
mitter, developed shortly after
ward by the Bell Company, not
only overcame this handicap
but was so fundamentally sound
that it was almost identical
with the one used today.
  </text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88078388/1934-10-25/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85038615/1913-04-13/ed-1/seq-36/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>

    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
